ACWA Education Department Records 5619/002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACWA Education Department Records
1990-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA)
5619/002
49 cubic feet
49 linear ft.
Records (documents), correspondence.
6849654
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
O. Familoni, October 07, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 21, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to settle disputes.
Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals.
Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.
Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.
During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.
Biographical / Historical
The Education Department informed members about the history, structure and functions of the union. It kept members and local union officers informed of policies and actions, industries with union members, legislative, and political issues. The Education Department also sought to promote social engagement among its members. The department conducted a number of conferences and institutes, including regional Education Department institutes specific to the needs of the local union members. The Education Department maintained a film library, made books on the labor movement available to members at discounted prices, ran a paperback library, and published local division newsletters.
Scope and Contents
The Education Department records span 1949 - 1983 with the bulk of the records from 1958 - 1979 These records document the department's outreach and public service activities, administrative meetings and functions, conferences and institutes, films, bookshelf projects and union labor actions.
Topics include election campaign and canvassing activities, Spanish-speaking and ADA voter registration, conferences, correspondence, reports, departmental publications, seminars, summer institutes, tours, purchasing department, staff meetings, resolutions, displays, finance, visitors, bills paid, form letters, materials requests, personnel, Joint Boards, AFL-CIO, films, scholarships, World Law Fund, legal, dues, minimum wage drives, Amalgamated News, newsletters, pamphlets, schools, paperback library, Environmental Action, Union Label, National Labor Service, Children International Summer Village, The Advance, labor bookshelf, Federation of Union Representatives, Coalition of Labor Union Women, strikes, textile industries, maps, plant closings, labor law reform, food stamps, ACTWU, labor problems, leadership training manual, steward manual, Orientation Kit J.P. Stevens, C.O.P.E., memos, consumer protection, Milton Watson, Bill Elkuss correspondence, George Guernsey, Joe Glazer, Senior Josephine Mastandrea, Vastina Wilson, R.J. Roper, and J. P. Stevens.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5619: ACWA Records 5619 AV: ACTWU Audio-Visual Materials 5619 C-S MB: ACTWU President Jack Sheinkman Additional Books, Memorabilia, and Files 5619 F: ACTWU Motion Picture Films 5619 G: ACTWU Graphics 5619 MB: ACTWU Memorabilia Collection 5619 mf: ACWA Records Parts 1-3 on Microfilm 5619 OH: ACWA Oral History Project Records 5619 P: ACTWU Photographs 5619 PUBS: ACTWU Publications 5619 PUBS: ACTWU Publications 5619/001: ACTWU Collective Bargaining Agreements 5619/003: ACWA's Sidney Hillman Scrapbooks, 1910-1964 5619/004: ACTWU President Jacob Sheinkman Files 5619/004 fiche: ACTWU President Jacob Sheinkman Speeches on Microfiche 5619/005: ACWA Bessie Hillman Papers 5619/006: ACTWU Executive Vice-President's Office Files 5619/007: ACTWU Organizing Department Files 5619/008: ACWA Rieve-Pollock Foundation Files 5619/009: ACTWU Operations Department Sidney Hillman Awards Files 5619/010: ACWA Jacob Potofsky files 5619/011: ACTWU Southern Regional Joint Board Files 5619/012: ACTWU Company Files 5619/013: ACTWU Research Department Correspondence Chronological Files 5619/014: ACWA Local 169 Files 5619/015: ACTWU Department of Occupational Safety and Health Files
Textile workers--Labor unions--New York (State); Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State); Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees --Archives; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives
6849654
- Registration Drive, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1958 Elections - Canvassers (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Registration, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Spanish and English
- 1958 Election Campaign (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Spanish speaking workers, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Education in the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Author: Lottie Haid Tartell
- ADA Voter Registration, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Central Labor Council Conference NYC Schools, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- NYS Committee on Fair Representation REAPP, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Panorama, Ever Forwarded, Highlights Requests, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- new members guide requests, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Purchasing Dept., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Reports, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  material requests
- Material published by this Department, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Film- Americans at work, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1965 Summer School Rutgers University (Box 1, Folder 16)
  July 25-30
- Southern School- Watts Bar Resort, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Oct. 5-9, 1965
- Washington Leg Conferences, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- UN tours, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Convention, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Displays, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Convention Bureau and UN tours, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Connie Kopelov: Acting National Director
- Staff meeting- May 1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Resolutions, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Transportation, Tours, NYC info, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mississippi School- Sardis Lake State Park, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Sept. 23-26, 1965
- Physical Education Conference, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Oct 24 and April 14
- Southern Legislative Conferences, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Laundry Workers Leadership Conference, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  May 28, 1965
- Laundry Workers, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  January 1965
- Conference on public education, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  June 12, 1965
- Contacts with Congressmen, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Conferences, Trips etc., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Education Staff, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The Inheritance two, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Finance, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Foreign Visitors, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Form Letters-outgoing-General, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Inter-Office, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Material Requests, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  INS leaflets
- Personnel, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Materials published by this department, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Purchasing, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Joint boards-B, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Chicago Joint Board, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Joint Boards M to P, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Milton Watson, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- South, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Joint Boards - S to W, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Laudry, StL, L.169, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous Joint Boards, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- AFL-CIO, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Cope Area Conference-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous Unions, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Film Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- A-B-C-D-E to Z, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Scholarships, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Rutgers University, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Rutgers University Programs, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- World Law Fund, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Mississippi School, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Southern School, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Oct 7-11
- Code Area Conference, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Film documentary material, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence memos- registration, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Staff meeting, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Meeting: January 17th, 1964
- Convention, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  resolution draft and format
- The Inheritance, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Material published by this department, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dues orders, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- APEC leaflets and buttons, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Staff meeting, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  January 1963
- Seminar 1959 Rutgers-Cornell Labor in American Politics, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NILE conference and AFL-CIO National Education Directors Conference, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  November 17-20 1959
- Legislation-Action, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 1958 Akers campaign (Box 3, Folder 13)
  17th CD
- Legislative campaigns, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Minimum wage drive, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Legislative Action Campaigns, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  January 1958
- Registration drive, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- IAM Education Bulletin, 1959-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 1960 Election Canvassers (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 1960 New York City Campaign- citizens and greater (Box 3, Folder 20)
  New York Committee on Registration
- UAW Washington Report, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- UAW Washington Report, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  months: January to December
- Truman Film (Sidney Hillman Foundation), 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The American Federationist, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Volume 77, September
- Film Ledger, 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- News from the hill, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Newsletter, Volume IV to V
- Negro History Conference, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Location: Washington D.C, December 8-10
- Copies of Book Club News, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Film for Amalgamated 40th Anniversary celebration, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  ACWA Convention
- Amalgamated News, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Minimum Wage Campaign, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Panorama Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- miscellaneous book pamphlets, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence on Schnapper book, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Textile-Books, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Not Paid
- Paperbacks Miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Conferences, Trips, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Southern Conferences, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Convention, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Executive, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Convention Orders, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Ottawa School, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  August 21-25
- Potosi Schools, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Summer School- Rutgers University, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- ACTWU Paperback Library, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Labor Unity Orders, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Paperback- Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Paperback Library- Bills not paid, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Paperback Library- Labor Unity orders, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Paperback Library- Bills Paid, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Paperback Library Returns, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Paperback Library - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- paperback Library- Bills not paid, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Paperback Library - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Book; "A Pictorial History", 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Author: William Cahn
- Manpower Training Program, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Reports, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Environmental Action, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Books Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Paperback Library- Bills Paid, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Returns, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Paperback Library Advance orders, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Returns, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- 1967 Eastern Summer School (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Rutgers University
- ACWA Midwestern Summer School, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Allerton Park, Illinois
- Washington Legislative Conferences, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- ACWA Staff Newsletter, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Midwest Summer School, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  August 11-17
- New Member Orders, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Your Dues, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- APEC Leaflet, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Staff Meetings, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Research equals Union Label, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Correspondence Joint Boards, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- AFL-CIO, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- A to E, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- F to N, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- R-S-W, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Schools of Universities, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Bills not paid, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Advance Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Letters to publishers, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Bills-Paid, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  Paperback Library
- Advance Orders, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Eastern Summer School, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  Rutgers
- Eastern Summer School, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Rutgers University, July 27- August 1
- Southern Summer Schools, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Southern Legislative Conferences, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Midwest School, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Conferences, Trips, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Executive, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Films Purchased by Organizations, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Finance, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Film Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- The Inheritance- Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- The Inheritance- Preview Requests, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Foreign Visitors, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Insurance, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Form Letters, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Outgoing-General
- Inter-Office, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Education Staff, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- William Elkuss- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Personnel, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Materials published by this Department, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Language: English and Spanish
- Purchasing, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Southern, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Staff Meeting, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Union Label, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Joint Boards A to B, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Chicago Joint Board, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Joint Boards C to P, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Joint Boards P to S, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Milton Watson, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous Joint Boards and Locals, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  English and Spanish
- Miscellaneous Unions, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- AFL-CIO, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Workers Educational Local 189, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  American Federation of Teachers
- Correspondence A to N, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Children International Summer Village, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- National Labor Service, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Correspondence O to Z, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Correspondence Souther Summer School, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Southern Schools, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- AFL-CIO Reprints, 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Collective Bargaining Report AFL-CIO, 1956-1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  consumer information
- Education, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Social Security Conference, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Location: Baltimore, Maryland. Topic: Medicare- ( Outline for Mobilizing Support)
- Rent Subsidy, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Newspaper
- Miscellaneous Voter Registration, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Bill Elkuss - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Inter-Office, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Material published by this Department, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Purchasing, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Personnel, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Reports, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Staff Meeting, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  May 22-23
- Joint Boards C to M, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Joint Boards G to W, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- South, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Milton Watson, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous Locals and Joint Boards, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- AFL-CIO, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Correspondence A to Z, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Local 189, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Bills Paid, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Conferences and Trips, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Summer School, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Executive, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Finance Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Foreign Visitors, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Inter-Office, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Personnel, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Purchasing and Materials published by this Department, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Philadelphia Legislative Conference, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  November13th, 1971
- Joint Boards A to Z, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Pittsburgh Legislative Institute, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  April 25-27
- Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Milton Watson, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Film Correspondence, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Bill Elkuss Correspondence, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- The Inheritance Preview Requests, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence A to Z, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- The Inheritance- Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- The Inheritance - Films purchased by Organizations, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- New York Urban Coalition, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  contains: The High School Project
- Voter Registration, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Union Leadership Academy, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Return Paper Back Books, 1963-1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- ACWA Paperback Library, 1963-1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Advance Correspondence, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Bills Paid, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Advance Orders, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- The Advance, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Congressional Visits, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Conferences, Trips, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Convention Resolutions, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Orders- Convention, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Summer School Sites, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Eastern Summer School, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Legislative Conferences, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Executive, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Education Department, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- William Elkuss Correspondence, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Film Correspondence, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Finance, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Foreign Visitors, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Inheritance-Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Inheritance - Preview Requests, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Inheritance - Purchased By Organizations, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Form Letters, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Outgoing - General
- Insurance, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Inter-Office, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)